Just like in the previous "sit" command, I would like you to administer baiting your dog with the "leave it" command as well.
Once your dog knows that they're about to have a work activity by baiting them, you can then get down on your one knee.
As I mentioned, I like to lightly hold the dog's collar, bait them so they know that a command is to follow.
I will be discussing placement of the treat or the object in an upcoming segment, but I'd like you to always think how baiting the dog gets the dog's attention.
Like I also mentioned, I never want a dog to assume a certain pattern of commands.
Certainly, if you go to a zoo or see a dog show, they train the dog to do a series of segments.
Good, sit.
But as far as the "leave it" command or any other single commands, I want the dog to know that baiting is going to be followed by a particular command.
Up.
Good, sit.